[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to English pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today
we're talking all about animals.
That's right. This is a very interesting
topic, very important because
well a lot of people like to have pets.
That's right. We're not going to the zoo.
We're not talking
about animals out in the
forest or in nature.
We're talking about pets
that you keep at home.
So let's start right away
with today's dialogue and we'll be back
in a moment to talk about what's going on.
We have been over this 100 times.
We are not getting a pet.
Why not? Come on.
Just a cute little puppy or kitty.
Who's going to look after a dog or a cat?
I will.
Affiliate, bathe it and walk it every day.
We can get a Labrador or a German Shepherd.
What if we want to take a vacation?
Who will we leave it with?
Plus, our apartment is too
small for that breed of dog.
Okay. How about we get a cat?
We're a ferret.
We're planning on
having children soon.
I don't think those animals are a
good idea with a baby in the house.
Fine. Let's get a bird then.
We can keep it in its
cage and teach it to talk.
Perit would be
awesome. I'll tell you what.
I can get you some hamsters
and we'll take it from there.
Yay!
All right. We're
back. Obviously, pets.
Having a pet at home is
a very big responsibility.
Well, this is what the
couple was talking about.
But before we get
into that discussion,
why don't we take a
look at five keywords that
we have picked out for
you on language takeaway?
Language takeaway. First
off, the couple is talking
about whether they
should get a dog or a cat or
a puppy or a kitty. And
when they start talking
about dogs, they talk
about what kinds of dogs
or the breed of the dogs.
Let's look at this word.
That's right. They
were talking about
a German Shepherd or a
Labrador. And as you said,
this is the breed or maybe
you can say a kind of dog.
That's right. So
breed is the technical
word to describe the kind
of dog that something is.
So like you said,
these are two examples.
There are many, many, many
breeds that we can talk about,
but we'll just leave
it at this for now.
But we talked about some
other kinds of animals today.
But we heard about some
other kinds of animals
today, not dogs, not cats,
maybe smaller animals.
That's right. One of the
animals that the person
mentioned was a
ferret. Ooh, ferret.
So this is a very small kind
of long animal. That's right.
You may have seen it heads
before. They kind of look
like, I don't know, kind
of they have the face of
a rat, maybe, but
they're very long.
And they're thin. They're
very thin. They're not like a rat
because maybe their body
shape is very, very different.
But they're, they're
also kind of small
and they like to eat. I
don't know if they have
long tails like rats do. I think
they have furies or different.
Yeah. So that's a ferret.
But we also heard about
a special kind of bird.
That's right. We talked about
a parrot. So as you know,
there are many
different kinds of birds.
You can see birds at
your window all the time.
But birds that come from
tropical places, usually
very, very colorful
birds are called parrots.
That's right. So a parrot usually can talk
or imitate what you say or sounds, right?
That's right. They're
actually very famous in
the bird world for
having a good ability to
reproduce or to mimic
the sounds that you make.
So if I say hello,
my parrot says hello.
Exactly. It's really
strange. They're very, very
intelligent animals.
So that's a parrot.
And our last animal
is a very small animal.
Very popular also to have is a
pet. We talked about a hamster.
A hamster. So this is
a little bit like a mouse.
They're furry. They're
small. They're round.
And they like, they live
in glass cages or fish tanks.
Usually. Yeah,
they're very small.
They don't really do much.
They're just little furry creatures.
And they, I don't know,
they just eat all day.
Sometimes they get
them those little wheels
that they can get inside
and run around all day.
That's right. Or when I
was a child and we had a
hamster, we had a special
plastic ball and you put
the hamster in the ball and
he would go around the house.
Yeah, exactly. It's
very fun. All right.
So we took a look at the
pets that that you can buy
domestic animals. But
taking a look at something
very specific when
they were describing the
responsibilities of having
maybe a dog or a cat,
they said they have to
feed it, bathe it, walk it.
So obviously we know
that feed it is to give it food.
But what about bathe it? Okay.
So you might know the
word bath. Okay. That's a thing.
It's a noun. Bathe
is a verb to bathe.
And so I can bathe myself.
That means I take a shower.
I clean my body or I can bathe
something else like an animal.
So bathing a dog means
basically washing a dog.
Right. So it sounds
very fancy or formal.
If you say, I'm going to
go take a shower or you say,
I'm going to go bathe. Yeah.
We don't really say that as much.
But we often say bathe when we're
talking about cleaning other things.
Not a table, but cleaning
people or animals. Right.
So you can say, did you bathe
the baby or did you bathe the dog?
Okay. So and also
remember that even though
the dog may be female or
male, we don't give it gender.
Right. We describe
it as it. That's right.
Animals are almost always
considered it in English.
Although some people who really love their
animals call it he or she. Right. Right.
So it's kind of your decision.
It's not really incorrect.
If you say, Oh, my
dog, she's so beautiful.
If it's a female. But you
know, technically you should
say, my dog, it's very
beautiful. Yeah. Okay.
So we've taken a look
at a lot of words there.
Why don't we go back, listen to
the dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
We have been over this a hundred times.
We are not getting a pet.
Why not? Come on. Just
a cute little puppy or kitty.
Who's going to look
after a dog or a cat?
I will. Affiliate, bathe
it and walk it every day.
We can get a Labrador
or a German Shepherd.
What if we want
to take a vacation?
Who will we leave it with?
Plus our apartment is too small
for that breed of dog. Okay.
How about we get a cat?
We're a ferret. We're planning
on having children soon.
I don't think those animals are a
good idea with a baby in the house. Fine.
Let's get a bird then.
We can keep it in its cage
and teach it to talk. A
pair would be awesome.
I'll tell you what. I can get you some
hamsters and we'll take it from there. Yay!
All right. We're back.
So now we've picked out
four key phrases for
you. Let's take a look
at those now in Fluency
Builder. Fluency Builder.
So at the very beginning
of today's conversation,
we hear the first person
say we've been over
this a hundred times.
So what does this mean?
This means that they've
never talked about this before?
No. This is actually the opposite,
but it's a way to exaggerate, right?
Because obviously they haven't
maybe talked about getting
a pet a hundred times,
but you're just making
emphasis on the fact
that we've talked about this
many, many, many times.
And almost like you're tired of it.
Like, oh, do we have
to talk about this again?
It's like you said, an
exaggeration to say, come on.
So we've been over
this a million times.
We've been over
this a hundred times.
These are always of saying,
we have to talk about this again.
Exactly. You're emphasizing
that, well, maybe
you've done it too many
times already. All right.
And well, when they
were talking about the pup
bee or the kitty, the
guy asked, well, who's
going to look after the
dog or the cat? Okay.
So this is an important
phrase. We're going to treat
this as a kind of a chunk. These
words go together to look after.
So we could look after a baby
or look after the pet. This
means to watch or to care for.
Right. To take care. So maybe if you're
going to go out tonight, you want to leave
your son with a
babysitter to look after him.
Right. To make sure that
there are no problems
or to make sure that he
eats and goes to sleep.
Exactly. So to look after to take
care or to make sure he or she is okay.
All right. And well, obviously, the guy
didn't want a puppy. He didn't want a kitty.
So the girl was giving
alternative and said,
well, how about we
get a cat or a ferret?
Okay. The phrase here,
how about is very, very
common in English. I
think a lot of people who
learn English have a hard
time knowing when to
use this phrase. How
about that's right.
So it's very simple. The
phrase, how about is to give
an alternative, right?
Okay. Or a suggestion.
So for example, you
and I are talking about
where to eat lunch. I don't
know. And you give a suggestion.
You say, how about pizza?
I say, I don't know.
How about McDonald's?
We're giving suggestions or
offering alternatives. Exactly.
So this is the correct way
of using how about many
students make the mistake of using it as
to say, how was it or how did it go? Right.
Right. So how is your
weekend? That's correct.
How about your
weekend? That's incorrect.
No. Do not say that. You
want to say, how about this?
How about that?
How about a Coke?
How about some food? These
are suggestions, but a real
question you have to
say, how was or how it is.
Right. So never, never, never
say, how about your weekend?
That is incorrect. And it's actually
very common to hear this from students.
So remember, it's not correct.
How about your weekend?
No, incorrect. So at the
very end of the dialogue,
we're talking about
hamsters. I can get you some
hamsters and we'll
take it from there.
That's right. The
phrase, take it from there.
It's kind of a way of saying,
look, let's start with something
small or let's start
with something simple,
and we will see how it
goes. So basically, the woman
is saying, I don't
want to commit.
I don't want to agree to get
a big animal, like a dog or a
cat, because I'm not
sure how it will be.
I'm not sure if it will be
too much responsibility.
So she's saying, okay, we'll
get something small and
then we'll wait and
we'll see what happens.
We'll take it from there.
That's right. So it's basically
saying, let's start slowly.
So for example, maybe
a guy asks you out, right, and
says, hey, will you marry me?
And you say, whoa, let's go on a
date first and we'll take it from there.
Exactly. We'll see what
happens. So let's start slowly.
Let's let's take
things step by step.
All right. So that's
all the phrases that we
have for you today. I
think we should listen to
the dialogue one last time, and
we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
We have been over this a hundred times.
We are not getting a pet.
Why not? Come on. Just
a cute little puppy or kitty.
Who's going to look
after a dog or a cat?
I will. I'll feed it, bathe
it, and walk it every day.
We can get a Labrador
or a German Shepherd.
What if we want to take a
vacation? Who will we leave it with?
Plus, our apartment is too
small for that breed of dog.
Okay. How about we
get a cat? We're a ferret.
We're planning on
having children soon.
I don't think those animals are a
good idea with a baby in the house.
Fine. Let's get a bird then.
We can keep it in its
cage and teach it to talk.
A pair would be
awesome. I'll tell you what.
I can get you some hamsters
and we'll take it from there.
Yay!
All right, Catherine.
So what about pets?
Are you a big pet
lover? Do you like ferrets?
Hamsters, all this good stuff. I
don't like small pets. I love big pets.
So as a kid, we had both. My
brother really loved small animals
like hamsters and ferrets
and things like that.
I just think they're a little bit stinky.
I think that's smell funny. So ever since,
I've always really liked
big animals like dogs.
So you are a dog
person. I am a dog person.
This is something interesting
that we describe in English.
People say I am a dog
person. I am a cat person.
It's almost like it says
something about your personality.
Exactly. So if you're a dog person, it
means that you prefer dogs or you like dogs.
If you're a cat person,
you prefer cats.
And a lot of people
really like dogs, but don't
really like cats. Or
they love cats and they
can't stand dogs. Right.
I think it even gets to
the point where I've
heard that maybe on dates,
people ask, "So are you a
dog person or a cat person?
" I know, that's
how I pick dates.
What about you? Are you a dog person or
a cat person? I'm definitely a dog person.
I good answer. Yeah, I
think cats are, I mean,
they're nice and
they're curly and they're,
I think they're very good indoor pets and
a little bit more fun than maybe a hamster.
But I think dogs have more life and are
more energetic. I think cats are very lazy.
And I think sometimes
cats like to play mind games.
Like they're so smart
that they can control you.
That makes me
uncomfortable. All right.
So well, there are a
lot of other pets out.
There are some people who
have tarantula, some people who
have iguanas, other people
who have fish, or horses.
Horses, if you have
enough space, right?
So we want to know what
kind of pets do you have or
did you have as a kid?
That's right. Let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there.
All right. Bye. Bye.